Sometimes our friends' behaviour can offend us; sometimes we can see changes they need to make – but how do we tell them?
有时朋友的行为会令我们不悦；有时我们能看出来他们需要做出改变——但我们该如何告诉他们呢？
Are there any ways to make difficult conversations easier?
有什么方法可以让不太友好的对话变得更容易吗？
It's important to have solid evidence that there is indeed a problem.
拥有确凿的证据证明确实存在问题是很重要的。
Evidence that can be agreed upon makes it easier for other people to recognise issues.
彼此都能够认可的证据可以让别人更容易认识到问题。
Once you have proof, it's important to highlight how it impacts us and others.
一旦你有了证据，强调它如何影响我们和他人是很重要的。
Psychologist Andrea Bonior suggests framing problems with 'I'.
心理学家安德里亚·博尼奥尔建议用"我"来表达问题。
Saying 'I feel hurt that you spend less time with me' is less accusatory than 'You never spend time with me!' and is focused more clearly on the impact.
说"我有些伤心，因为你花在我身上的时间少了"比"你从不花时间陪我！"更少指责性，并且更清晰地聚焦于影响。
Staying calm is vital.
保持冷静至关重要。
Becoming tense might lead you to react badly and cause an argument.
变得紧张可能导致你反应糟糕，引发争吵。
Bonior recommends that you should acknowledge the conversation could make you anxious.
博尼奥尔建议，你应该承认这次对话可能会让你焦虑。
If you think about this yourself, it can help you focus on positive results.
如果你自己想到这一点，它能帮助你专注于积极的结果。
If you admit your anxiety to your friend, you will show a more human side.
如果你向朋友承认你的焦虑，你会展现出更人性化的一面。
Another psychologist, Laura Brennan, points out how it's important that we let go of our ego and don't focus on the need to be proved right.
另一位心理学家劳拉·布伦南指出，我们放下自我，不专注于证明自己是正确的，这一点很重要。
This can help reduce tension.
这有助于减少焦虑。
We can lower the potential for conflict by listening to the other person and asking questions.
我们可以通过倾听对方和提问来降低冲突的可能性。
Many experts recommend planning your words, so that you can say things in a way that avoids conflict.
许多专家建议提前计划好你的措辞，这样你就可以用一种避免冲突的方式说话。
However, Bonior cautions against overplanning as this can stop you being flexible enough to genuinely follow and participate in the discussion.
然而，博尼奥尔警告不要过度计划，因为这可能会阻止你足够灵活地真正理解并参与讨论。
Be realistic.
面对现实。
Complicated problems are unlikely to be solved with one conversation.
复杂的问题不太可能通过一次对话就解决。
Consider what is possible in one discussion, and that it may be harder than you initially thought.
思考一下一次讨论中可能实现什么，并且这次讨论可能比你最初认为的还要困难。
This will help you to set realistic goals for what you can achieve.
这将有助于设定你能实现的现实可行的目标。